<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Horea Porutiu</title>
    <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Horea Porutiu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 11:11:20 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://horeaporutiu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emit Conference</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/emit-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 11:11:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/emit-conference/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever thought of going into Dev-Ops? Ever thought of all of the work that goes into hosting and providing an application that is viewable all across the globe, regardless of how many users are using the app at one time? Well that is what the Dev-Ops engineers work on, all the time. The promise of serverless and event-driven architectures, which is what Emit Conference was based on, takes this notion of Dev-Ops and automates it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Cloudant Database via Rest API</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/updating-cloudant-database-via-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 11:11:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/updating-cloudant-database-via-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>Trying to update your Cloudant Database via REST API? Not sure how to get started? You&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll teach you how to update your database programmatically using Node.js and REST API calls. As a bonus, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to keep track of the objects in your database, and how to sort your database according to your most popular objects.
I will assume you have created a Cloudant account through IBM Cloud &amp;ldquo;Bluemix&amp;rdquo;, and have created a database and a document through the Cloudant UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Token Authentication with OpenWhisk</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/token-authentication-with-openwhisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 15:56:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/token-authentication-with-openwhisk/</guid>
      <description>Ready to launch that sweet Web-App that sweeps Siri out of the water? If so, you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place. I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to  generate a token server-side for Watson&amp;rsquo;s Speech To Text Service in your Web-App.
OpenWhisk Now you may be thinking&amp;hellip;OpenWhisk? Why not use Node.js? Everyone knows Node, and there&amp;rsquo;s much more documentation if I get stuck. While I cannot refute the last statement, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you why using a new technology like OpenWhisk, similar to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Lambda, might save you cash down the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWhisk Web Actions and REST API calls</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/openwhisk-web-actions-and-rest-api-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 15:34:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/openwhisk-web-actions-and-rest-api-calls/</guid>
      <description>Demo of the finished product:
  
In this blog post, i&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to use IBM&amp;rsquo;s Function-as-a-Service (Faas), OpenWhisk, to build a basic translation app. Our app will get its data by using REST API calls to talk to Watson. Keep in mind that you could use any sort of back end written in any langauge you want, but I chose OpenWhisk since I wanted to get familiar working with a Function-as-a-Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on my first few months at IBM</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-my-first-few-months-at-ibm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 16:14:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-my-first-few-months-at-ibm/</guid>
      <description>As part of being a new hire, I was asked to share what I have learned in my first few months at IBM. I decided it would be a good topic for a blog post, and although it does not entirely fit the Emerging Techonology theme of my blog, I think it will be relevant for others going into this field, or any other professional field in general. The two biggest lessons I want to explore in this post are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF IoT Meetup</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/sf-iot-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 16:14:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/sf-iot-meetup/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I went to a couple meet ups one of which being the SF IoT Meetup. The Meetup was hosted at APROE, a design and engineering firm. The venue was filled with machines and had an interesting electronics lab, which proved to be useful later when soldering was necessary for the Raspberry Pi kit. The Meetup was a hands-on workshop hosted by Taku Tamagawa, the head of Operations at Soracom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Approaches to API Calls with Server-Side Swift</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/two-approaches-to-api-calls-with-server-side-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 16:14:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/two-approaches-to-api-calls-with-server-side-swift/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, i&amp;rsquo;m going to go over how to make an HTTP Post Request using Kitura (A Server-Side Swift Framework). First i&amp;rsquo;ll be making Post Requests using URLSession, and then using KituraNet. If you are not sure how to start up a Kitura project, go here. If you want to see another implementation of a HTTP Post Request with KituraNet, Rob Allen does a great job explaining his code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 at Augmented World Expo</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/day-2-at-augmented-world-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/day-2-at-augmented-world-expo/</guid>
      <description>The second day at AWE proved to be really really incredible. The biggest difference between the two days was that the Expo was open today, giving me the ability to try out all of the cool gadgets and headsets that I learned about previously. Some proved to be great, and others not so great. Ill give my thoughts on the speakers that I saw from Meta, Schell Games, and Kopin Corporation, as well as the products I tried out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 at Augmented World Expo</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/day-1-at-augmented-world-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/day-1-at-augmented-world-expo/</guid>
      <description>Today was my first day at AWE(Augmented World Expo), and other than waking up much earlier than usual (around 730), it was a pretty great day. On a complete side note, I learned to navigate the Caltrain today, which was nice. Especially since it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to get to the San Jose, South Bay area without having to deal with the rush hour traffic.
In this blog, I am going to give my thoughts around my first big conference experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Augmented Reality</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/intro-to-augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/intro-to-augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>So first and foremost I want to make a shoutout to Jacob W. Green, who wrote this great post about getting started with Augmented Reality. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to follow, and very informative. His post uses augmented reality to overlay an image of an author over the cover of the corresponding book. Now this may or may not sound appealing to you, but I am extremely excited to be going to AWE (Augmented World Expo) next week, and what better way to get familiar with AR than by building a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Watson &amp;&amp; Kitura</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/connecting-watson--kitura/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/connecting-watson--kitura/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys! I haven&amp;rsquo;t written in a bit since I was exploring some cool technologies. In the past week, i&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work learning about Kitura. In this blog, I will explain what I have learned, and help you get started learning Kitura and integrating your apps with Watson. Below is an iOS app that integrates text to speech and language translation services from watson. The source code to get started can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to: Blog w/ Hugo and Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/how-to-blog-w/-hugo-and-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/how-to-blog-w/-hugo-and-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial focuses on building exactly this: a Hugo site! If you follow these two videos, you should be able to build your own site and customize it within minutes. Please feel free to ask questions or drop some suggestions below!
 Setup Your Blog   Customize!   Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWhisk Actions &amp; API calls</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/openwhisk-actions--api-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/openwhisk-actions--api-calls/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I will go over some of the basics of OpenWhisk and go over a simple example of an action that will load weather for your area. I assume you already have a Bluemix account. If you do not, go here to get one. 
Initial Setup 1) Setup OpenWhisk CLI (Command Line Interface). If you&amp;rsquo;ve verified your setup from the setup above, you should be good to go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Node.js server with Bluemix</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/run-node.js-server-with-bluemix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 14:18:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/blog/run-node.js-server-with-bluemix/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s learn how to build that Node.js web-server using Bluemix! If you prefer video tutorials, please watch the video below.
 Before we start, you will need to do a few things.
 Initial Setup 1) Get a Bluemix Account
2) Install Homebrew if you have a mac. Otherwise, skip this step.
3) Install npm/node for Mac or npm/node for Windows
4) Install cf command line tool
Starter Code Open up terminal, and use the following git commands: $ git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://horeaporutiu.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy writing code and being outside. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a Developer Advocate for IBM, promoting IBM&amp;rsquo;s Platform-As-A-Service Bluemix. I graduated from UC San Diego in March 2017 with a double major in Computer &amp;amp; Management Science. I played tennis for the UC San Diego Men&amp;rsquo;s Tennis Team where I was awarded team MVP, and reached a NCAA National Ranking of 13 with partner Alex Miaule.When I was not on the court, I was in the classroom or at office hours trying to excel in my classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>